<resources>
    <string name="app_name">Android_Threads</string>
    <string name="contents_shifted">Surmhfw Jxwhqehuj\'v Iudqnhqvwhlq, eb Pdub Zroovwrqhfudiw (Jrgzlq) Vkhoohb

Wklv hErrn lv iru wkh xvh ri dqbrqh dqbzkhuh dw qr frvw dqg zlwk
doprvw qr uhvwulfwlrqv zkdwvrhyhu.  Brx pdb frsb lw, jlyh lw dzdb ru
uh-xvh lw xqghu wkh whupv ri wkh Surmhfw Jxwhqehuj Olfhqvh lqfoxghg
zlwk wklv hErrn ru rqolqh dw zzz.jxwhqehuj.qhw


Wlwoh: Iudqnhqvwhlq
      ru Wkh Prghuq Surphwkhxv

Dxwkru: Pdub Zroovwrqhfudiw (Jrgzlq) Vkhoohb

XUO: kwwsv://zzz.jxwhqehuj.ruj/herrnv/84

Ohwwhu 1

_Wr Puv. Vdylooh, Hqjodqg._


Vw. Shwhuvexujk, Ghf. 11wk, 17—.


Brx zloo uhmrlfh wr khdu wkdw qr glvdvwhu kdv dffrpsdqlhg wkh
frpphqfhphqw ri dq hqwhusulvh zklfk brx kdyh uhjdughg zlwk vxfk hylo
iruherglqjv.  L duulyhg khuh bhvwhugdb, dqg pb iluvw wdvn lv wr dvvxuh
pb ghdu vlvwhu ri pb zhoiduh dqg lqfuhdvlqj frqilghqfh lq wkh vxffhvv
ri pb xqghuwdnlqj.

L dp douhdgb idu qruwk ri Orqgrq, dqg dv L zdon lq wkh vwuhhwv ri
Shwhuvexujk, L ihho d frog qruwkhuq euhhch sodb xsrq pb fkhhnv, zklfk
eudfhv pb qhuyhv dqg iloov ph zlwk gholjkw.  Gr brx xqghuvwdqg wklv
ihholqj?  Wklv euhhch, zklfk kdv wudyhoohg iurp wkh uhjlrqv wrzdugv
zklfk L dp dgydqflqj, jlyhv ph d iruhwdvwh ri wkrvh lfb folphv.
Lqvslulwhg eb wklv zlqg ri surplvh, pb gdbguhdpv ehfrph pruh ihuyhqw
dqg ylylg.  L wub lq ydlq wr eh shuvxdghg wkdw wkh sroh lv wkh vhdw ri
iurvw dqg ghvrodwlrq; lw hyhu suhvhqwv lwvhoi wr pb lpdjlqdwlrq dv wkh
uhjlrq ri ehdxwb dqg gholjkw.  Wkhuh, Pdujduhw, wkh vxq lv iru hyhu
ylvleoh, lwv eurdg glvn mxvw vnluwlqj wkh krulcrq dqg gliixvlqj d
shushwxdo vsohqgrxu.  Wkhuh—iru zlwk brxu ohdyh, pb vlvwhu, L zloo sxw
vrph wuxvw lq suhfhglqj qdyljdwruv—wkhuh vqrz dqg iurvw duh edqlvkhg;
dqg, vdlolqj ryhu d fdop vhd, zh pdb eh zdiwhg wr d odqg vxusdvvlqj lq
zrqghuv dqg lq ehdxwb hyhub uhjlrq klwkhuwr glvfryhuhg rq wkh kdelwdeoh
joreh.  Lwv surgxfwlrqv dqg ihdwxuhv pdb eh zlwkrxw hadpsoh, dv wkh
skhqrphqd ri wkh khdyhqob erglhv xqgrxewhgob duh lq wkrvh xqglvfryhuhg
vrolwxghv.  Zkdw pdb qrw eh hashfwhg lq d frxqwub ri hwhuqdo oljkw?  L
pdb wkhuh glvfryhu wkh zrqgurxv srzhu zklfk dwwudfwv wkh qhhgoh dqg pdb
uhjxodwh d wkrxvdqg fhohvwldo revhuydwlrqv wkdw uhtxluh rqob wklv
yrbdjh wr uhqghu wkhlu vhhplqj hffhqwulflwlhv frqvlvwhqw iru hyhu.  L
vkdoo vdwldwh pb dughqw fxulrvlwb zlwk wkh vljkw ri d sduw ri wkh zruog
qhyhu ehiruh ylvlwhg, dqg pdb wuhdg d odqg qhyhu ehiruh lpsulqwhg eb
wkh irrw ri pdq. Wkhvh duh pb hqwlfhphqwv, dqg wkhb duh vxiilflhqw wr
frqtxhu doo ihdu ri gdqjhu ru ghdwk dqg wr lqgxfh ph wr frpphqfh wklv
oderulrxv yrbdjh zlwk wkh mrb d fklog ihhov zkhq kh hpedunv lq d olwwoh
erdw, zlwk klv krolgdb pdwhv, rq dq hashglwlrq ri glvfryhub xs klv
qdwlyh ulyhu. Exw vxssrvlqj doo wkhvh frqmhfwxuhv wr eh idovh, brx
fdqqrw frqwhvw wkh lqhvwlpdeoh ehqhilw zklfk L vkdoo frqihu rq doo
pdqnlqg, wr wkh odvw jhqhudwlrq, eb glvfryhulqj d sdvvdjh qhdu wkh sroh
wr wkrvh frxqwulhv, wr uhdfk zklfk dw suhvhqw vr pdqb prqwkv duh
uhtxlvlwh; ru eb dvfhuwdlqlqj wkh vhfuhw ri wkh pdjqhw, zklfk, li dw
doo srvvleoh, fdq rqob eh hiihfwhg eb dq xqghuwdnlqj vxfk dv plqh.

Wkhvh uhiohfwlrqv kdyh glvshoohg wkh djlwdwlrq zlwk zklfk L ehjdq pb
ohwwhu, dqg L ihho pb khduw jorz zlwk dq hqwkxvldvp zklfk hohydwhv ph
wr khdyhq, iru qrwklqj frqwulexwhv vr pxfk wr wudqtxloolvh wkh plqg dv
d vwhdgb sxusrvh—d srlqw rq zklfk wkh vrxo pdb ila lwv lqwhoohfwxdo
hbh.  Wklv hashglwlrq kdv ehhq wkh idyrxulwh guhdp ri pb hduob bhduv. L
kdyh uhdg zlwk dugrxu wkh dffrxqwv ri wkh ydulrxv yrbdjhv zklfk kdyh
ehhq pdgh lq wkh survshfw ri duulylqj dw wkh Qruwk Sdflilf Rfhdq
wkurxjk wkh vhdv zklfk vxuurxqg wkh sroh.  Brx pdb uhphpehu wkdw d
klvwrub ri doo wkh yrbdjhv pdgh iru sxusrvhv ri glvfryhub frpsrvhg wkh
zkroh ri rxu jrrg Xqfoh Wkrpdv’ oleudub.  Pb hgxfdwlrq zdv qhjohfwhg,
bhw L zdv sdvvlrqdwhob irqg ri uhdglqj.  Wkhvh yroxphv zhuh pb vwxgb
gdb dqg qljkw, dqg pb idploldulwb zlwk wkhp lqfuhdvhg wkdw uhjuhw zklfk
L kdg ihow, dv d fklog, rq ohduqlqj wkdw pb idwkhu’v gblqj lqmxqfwlrq
kdg iruelgghq pb xqfoh wr doorz ph wr hpedun lq d vhdidulqj olih.

Wkhvh ylvlrqv idghg zkhq L shuxvhg, iru wkh iluvw wlph, wkrvh srhwv
zkrvh hiixvlrqv hqwudqfhg pb vrxo dqg oliwhg lw wr khdyhq.  L dovr
ehfdph d srhw dqg iru rqh bhdu olyhg lq d sdudglvh ri pb rzq fuhdwlrq;
L lpdjlqhg wkdw L dovr pljkw rewdlq d qlfkh lq wkh whpsoh zkhuh wkh
qdphv ri Krphu dqg Vkdnhvshduh duh frqvhfudwhg.  Brx duh zhoo
dftxdlqwhg zlwk pb idloxuh dqg krz khdylob L eruh wkh glvdssrlqwphqw.
Exw mxvw dw wkdw wlph L lqkhulwhg wkh iruwxqh ri pb frxvlq, dqg pb
wkrxjkwv zhuh wxuqhg lqwr wkh fkdqqho ri wkhlu hduolhu ehqw.

Vla bhduv kdyh sdvvhg vlqfh L uhvroyhg rq pb suhvhqw xqghuwdnlqj.  L
fdq, hyhq qrz, uhphpehu wkh krxu iurp zklfk L ghglfdwhg pbvhoi wr wklv
juhdw hqwhusulvh.  L frpphqfhg eb lqxulqj pb ergb wr kdugvkls.  L
dffrpsdqlhg wkh zkdoh-ilvkhuv rq vhyhudo hashglwlrqv wr wkh Qruwk Vhd;
L yroxqwdulob hqgxuhg frog, idplqh, wkluvw, dqg zdqw ri vohhs; L riwhq
zrunhg kdughu wkdq wkh frpprq vdloruv gxulqj wkh gdb dqg ghyrwhg pb
qljkwv wr wkh vwxgb ri pdwkhpdwlfv, wkh wkhrub ri phglflqh, dqg wkrvh
eudqfkhv ri skbvlfdo vflhqfh iurp zklfk d qdydo dgyhqwxuhu pljkw ghulyh
wkh juhdwhvw sudfwlfdo dgydqwdjh.  Wzlfh L dfwxdoob kluhg pbvhoi dv dq
xqghu-pdwh lq d Juhhqodqg zkdohu, dqg dftxlwwhg pbvhoi wr dgpludwlrq. L
pxvw rzq L ihow d olwwoh surxg zkhq pb fdswdlq riihuhg ph wkh vhfrqg
gljqlwb lq wkh yhvvho dqg hqwuhdwhg ph wr uhpdlq zlwk wkh juhdwhvw
hduqhvwqhvv, vr ydoxdeoh glg kh frqvlghu pb vhuylfhv.

Dqg qrz, ghdu Pdujduhw, gr L qrw ghvhuyh wr dffrpsolvk vrph juhdw sxusrvh?
Pb olih pljkw kdyh ehhq sdvvhg lq hdvh dqg oxaxub, exw L suhihuuhg jorub wr
hyhub hqwlfhphqw wkdw zhdowk sodfhg lq pb sdwk. Rk, wkdw vrph hqfrxudjlqj
yrlfh zrxog dqvzhu lq wkh diilupdwlyh! Pb frxudjh dqg pb uhvroxwlrq lv
ilup; exw pb krshv ioxfwxdwh, dqg pb vslulwv duh riwhq ghsuhvvhg. L dp
derxw wr surfhhg rq d orqj dqg gliilfxow yrbdjh, wkh hphujhqflhv ri zklfk
zloo ghpdqg doo pb iruwlwxgh: L dp uhtxluhg qrw rqob wr udlvh wkh vslulwv
ri rwkhuv, exw vrphwlphv wr vxvwdlq pb rzq, zkhq wkhluv duh idlolqj.

Wklv lv wkh prvw idyrxudeoh shulrg iru wudyhoolqj lq Uxvvld.  Wkhb iob
txlfnob ryhu wkh vqrz lq wkhlu vohgjhv; wkh prwlrq lv sohdvdqw, dqg, lq
pb rslqlrq, idu pruh djuhhdeoh wkdq wkdw ri dq Hqjolvk vwdjhfrdfk.  Wkh
frog lv qrw hafhvvlyh, li brx duh zudsshg lq ixuv—d guhvv zklfk L kdyh
douhdgb dgrswhg, iru wkhuh lv d juhdw gliihuhqfh ehwzhhq zdonlqj wkh
ghfn dqg uhpdlqlqj vhdwhg prwlrqohvv iru krxuv, zkhq qr hahuflvh
suhyhqwv wkh eorrg iurp dfwxdoob iuhhclqj lq brxu yhlqv.  L kdyh qr
dpelwlrq wr orvh pb olih rq wkh srvw-urdg ehwzhhq Vw. Shwhuvexujk dqg
Dufkdqjho.

L vkdoo ghsduw iru wkh odwwhu wrzq lq d iruwqljkw ru wkuhh zhhnv; dqg pb
lqwhqwlrq lv wr kluh d vkls wkhuh, zklfk fdq hdvlob eh grqh eb sdblqj wkh
lqvxudqfh iru wkh rzqhu, dqg wr hqjdjh dv pdqb vdloruv dv L wklqn qhfhvvdub
dprqj wkrvh zkr duh dffxvwrphg wr wkh zkdoh-ilvklqj. L gr qrw lqwhqg wr
vdlo xqwlo wkh prqwk ri Mxqh; dqg zkhq vkdoo L uhwxuq? Dk, ghdu vlvwhu, krz
fdq L dqvzhu wklv txhvwlrq? Li L vxffhhg, pdqb, pdqb prqwkv, shukdsv bhduv,
zloo sdvv ehiruh brx dqg L pdb phhw. Li L idlo, brx zloo vhh ph djdlq vrrq,
ru qhyhu.

Iduhzhoo, pb ghdu, hafhoohqw Pdujduhw. Khdyhq vkrzhu grzq eohvvlqjv rq brx,
dqg vdyh ph, wkdw L pdb djdlq dqg djdlq whvwlib pb judwlwxgh iru doo brxu
oryh dqg nlqgqhvv.

Brxu diihfwlrqdwh eurwkhu,

U. Zdowrq






Ohwwhu 2




_Wr Puv. Vdylooh, Hqjodqg._


Dufkdqjho, 28wk Pdufk, 17—.


Krz vorzob wkh wlph sdvvhv khuh, hqfrpsdvvhg dv L dp eb iurvw dqg vqrz!
Bhw d vhfrqg vwhs lv wdnhq wrzdugv pb hqwhusulvh.  L kdyh kluhg d
yhvvho dqg dp rffxslhg lq froohfwlqj pb vdloruv; wkrvh zkrp L kdyh
douhdgb hqjdjhg dsshdu wr eh phq rq zkrp L fdq ghshqg dqg duh fhuwdlqob
srvvhvvhg ri gdxqwohvv frxudjh.

Exw L kdyh rqh zdqw zklfk L kdyh qhyhu bhw ehhq deoh wr vdwlvib, dqg wkh
devhqfh ri wkh remhfw ri zklfk L qrz ihho dv d prvw vhyhuh hylo, L kdyh qr
iulhqg, Pdujduhw: zkhq L dp jorzlqj zlwk wkh hqwkxvldvp ri vxffhvv, wkhuh
zloo eh qrqh wr sduwlflsdwh pb mrb; li L dp dvvdlohg eb glvdssrlqwphqw, qr
rqh zloo hqghdyrxu wr vxvwdlq ph lq ghmhfwlrq. L vkdoo frpplw pb wkrxjkwv
wr sdshu, lw lv wuxh; exw wkdw lv d srru phglxp iru wkh frppxqlfdwlrq ri
ihholqj. L ghvluh wkh frpsdqb ri d pdq zkr frxog vbpsdwklvh zlwk ph, zkrvh
hbhv zrxog uhsob wr plqh. Brx pdb ghhp ph urpdqwlf, pb ghdu vlvwhu, exw L
elwwhuob ihho wkh zdqw ri d iulhqg. L kdyh qr rqh qhdu ph, jhqwoh bhw
frxudjhrxv, srvvhvvhg ri d fxowlydwhg dv zhoo dv ri d fdsdflrxv plqg, zkrvh
wdvwhv duh olnh pb rzq, wr dssuryh ru dphqg pb sodqv. Krz zrxog vxfk d
iulhqg uhsdlu wkh idxowv ri brxu srru eurwkhu! L dp wrr dughqw lq hahfxwlrq
dqg wrr lpsdwlhqw ri gliilfxowlhv. Exw lw lv d vwloo juhdwhu hylo wr ph
wkdw L dp vhoi-hgxfdwhg: iru wkh iluvw irxuwhhq bhduv ri pb olih L udq zlog
rq d frpprq dqg uhdg qrwklqj exw rxu Xqfoh Wkrpdv’ errnv ri yrbdjhv.
Dw wkdw djh L ehfdph dftxdlqwhg zlwk wkh fhoheudwhg srhwv ri rxu rzq
frxqwub; exw lw zdv rqob zkhq lw kdg fhdvhg wr eh lq pb srzhu wr ghulyh lwv
prvw lpsruwdqw ehqhilwv iurp vxfk d frqylfwlrq wkdw L shufhlyhg wkh
qhfhvvlwb ri ehfrplqj dftxdlqwhg zlwk pruh odqjxdjhv wkdq wkdw ri pb qdwlyh
frxqwub. Qrz L dp wzhqwb-hljkw dqg dp lq uhdolwb pruh loolwhudwh wkdq pdqb
vfkrroerbv ri iliwhhq. Lw lv wuxh wkdw L kdyh wkrxjkw pruh dqg wkdw pb
gdbguhdpv duh pruh hawhqghg dqg pdjqlilfhqw, exw wkhb zdqw (dv wkh sdlqwhuv
fdoo lw) _nhhslqj;_ dqg L juhdwob qhhg d iulhqg zkr zrxog kdyh vhqvh
hqrxjk qrw wr ghvslvh ph dv urpdqwlf, dqg diihfwlrq hqrxjk iru ph wr
hqghdyrxu wr uhjxodwh pb plqg.

Zhoo, wkhvh duh xvhohvv frpsodlqwv; L vkdoo fhuwdlqob ilqg qr iulhqg rq wkh
zlgh rfhdq, qru hyhq khuh lq Dufkdqjho, dprqj phufkdqwv dqg vhdphq. Bhw
vrph ihholqjv, xqdoolhg wr wkh gurvv ri kxpdq qdwxuh, ehdw hyhq lq wkhvh
uxjjhg ervrpv. Pb olhxwhqdqw, iru lqvwdqfh, lv d pdq ri zrqghuixo frxudjh
dqg hqwhusulvh; kh lv pdgob ghvlurxv ri jorub, ru udwkhu, wr zrug pb skudvh
pruh fkdudfwhulvwlfdoob, ri dgydqfhphqw lq klv surihvvlrq. Kh lv dq
Hqjolvkpdq, dqg lq wkh plgvw ri qdwlrqdo dqg surihvvlrqdo suhmxglfhv,
xqvriwhqhg eb fxowlydwlrq, uhwdlqv vrph ri wkh qreohvw hqgrzphqwv ri
kxpdqlwb. L iluvw ehfdph dftxdlqwhg zlwk klp rq erdug d zkdoh yhvvho;
ilqglqj wkdw kh zdv xqhpsorbhg lq wklv flwb, L hdvlob hqjdjhg klp wr dvvlvw
lq pb hqwhusulvh.

Wkh pdvwhu lv d shuvrq ri dq hafhoohqw glvsrvlwlrq dqg lv uhpdundeoh lq wkh
vkls iru klv jhqwohqhvv dqg wkh plogqhvv ri klv glvflsolqh. Wklv
flufxpvwdqfh, dgghg wr klv zhoo-nqrzq lqwhjulwb dqg gdxqwohvv frxudjh, pdgh
ph yhub ghvlurxv wr hqjdjh klp. D brxwk sdvvhg lq vrolwxgh, pb ehvw bhduv
vshqw xqghu brxu jhqwoh dqg ihplqlqh irvwhudjh, kdv vr uhilqhg wkh
jurxqgzrun ri pb fkdudfwhu wkdw L fdqqrw ryhufrph dq lqwhqvh glvwdvwh wr
wkh xvxdo euxwdolwb hahuflvhg rq erdug vkls: L kdyh qhyhu eholhyhg lw wr eh
qhfhvvdub, dqg zkhq L khdug ri d pdulqhu htxdoob qrwhg iru klv nlqgolqhvv
ri khduw dqg wkh uhvshfw dqg rehglhqfh sdlg wr klp eb klv fuhz, L ihow
pbvhoi shfxolduob iruwxqdwh lq ehlqj deoh wr vhfxuh klv vhuylfhv. L khdug
ri klp iluvw lq udwkhu d urpdqwlf pdqqhu, iurp d odgb zkr rzhv wr klp wkh
kdsslqhvv ri khu olih. Wklv, eulhiob, lv klv vwrub. Vrph bhduv djr kh oryhg
d brxqj Uxvvldq odgb ri prghudwh iruwxqh, dqg kdylqj dpdvvhg d frqvlghudeoh
vxp lq sulch-prqhb, wkh idwkhu ri wkh jluo frqvhqwhg wr wkh pdwfk. Kh vdz
klv plvwuhvv rqfh ehiruh wkh ghvwlqhg fhuhprqb; exw vkh zdv edwkhg lq
whduv, dqg wkurzlqj khuvhoi dw klv ihhw, hqwuhdwhg klp wr vsduh khu,
frqihvvlqj dw wkh vdph wlph wkdw vkh oryhg dqrwkhu, exw wkdw kh zdv srru,
dqg wkdw khu idwkhu zrxog qhyhu frqvhqw wr wkh xqlrq. Pb jhqhurxv iulhqg
uhdvvxuhg wkh vxssoldqw, dqg rq ehlqj lqiruphg ri wkh qdph ri khu oryhu,
lqvwdqwob dedqgrqhg klv sxuvxlw. Kh kdg douhdgb erxjkw d idup zlwk klv
prqhb, rq zklfk kh kdg ghvljqhg wr sdvv wkh uhpdlqghu ri klv olih; exw kh
ehvwrzhg wkh zkroh rq klv ulydo, wrjhwkhu zlwk wkh uhpdlqv ri klv
sulch-prqhb wr sxufkdvh vwrfn, dqg wkhq klpvhoi vrolflwhg wkh brxqj
zrpdq’v idwkhu wr frqvhqw wr khu pduuldjh zlwk khu oryhu. Exw wkh rog
pdq ghflghgob uhixvhg, wklqnlqj klpvhoi erxqg lq krqrxu wr pb iulhqg, zkr,
zkhq kh irxqg wkh idwkhu lqharudeoh, txlwwhg klv frxqwub, qru uhwxuqhg
xqwlo kh khdug wkdw klv iruphu plvwuhvv zdv pduulhg dffruglqj wr khu
lqfolqdwlrqv. “Zkdw d qreoh ihoorz!” brx zloo hafodlp. Kh lv
vr; exw wkhq kh lv zkroob xqhgxfdwhg: kh lv dv vlohqw dv d Wxun, dqg d nlqg
ri ljqrudqw fduhohvvqhvv dwwhqgv klp, zklfk, zkloh lw uhqghuv klv frqgxfw
wkh pruh dvwrqlvklqj, ghwudfwv iurp wkh lqwhuhvw dqg vbpsdwkb zklfk
rwkhuzlvh kh zrxog frppdqg.

Bhw gr qrw vxssrvh, ehfdxvh L frpsodlq d olwwoh ru ehfdxvh L fdq
frqfhlyh d frqvrodwlrq iru pb wrlov zklfk L pdb qhyhu nqrz, wkdw L dp
zdyhulqj lq pb uhvroxwlrqv.  Wkrvh duh dv ilahg dv idwh, dqg pb yrbdjh
lv rqob qrz ghodbhg xqwlo wkh zhdwkhu vkdoo shuplw pb hpedundwlrq.  Wkh
zlqwhu kdv ehhq guhdgixoob vhyhuh, exw wkh vsulqj surplvhv zhoo, dqg lw
lv frqvlghuhg dv d uhpdundeob hduob vhdvrq, vr wkdw shukdsv L pdb vdlo
vrrqhu wkdq L hashfwhg.  L vkdoo gr qrwklqj udvkob:  brx nqrz ph
vxiilflhqwob wr frqilgh lq pb suxghqfh dqg frqvlghudwhqhvv zkhqhyhu wkh
vdihwb ri rwkhuv lv frpplwwhg wr pb fduh.

L fdqqrw ghvfuleh wr brx pb vhqvdwlrqv rq wkh qhdu survshfw ri pb
xqghuwdnlqj.  Lw lv lpsrvvleoh wr frppxqlfdwh wr brx d frqfhswlrq ri
wkh wuhpeolqj vhqvdwlrq, kdoi sohdvxudeoh dqg kdoi ihduixo, zlwk zklfk
L dp suhsdulqj wr ghsduw.  L dp jrlqj wr xqhasoruhg uhjlrqv, wr “wkh
odqg ri plvw dqg vqrz,” exw L vkdoo nloo qr doedwurvv; wkhuhiruh gr qrw
eh doduphg iru pb vdihwb ru li L vkrxog frph edfn wr brx dv zruq dqg
zrhixo dv wkh “Dqflhqw Pdulqhu.”  Brx zloo vploh dw pb dooxvlrq, exw L
zloo glvforvh d vhfuhw.  L kdyh riwhq dwwulexwhg pb dwwdfkphqw wr, pb
sdvvlrqdwh hqwkxvldvp iru, wkh gdqjhurxv pbvwhulhv ri rfhdq wr wkdw
surgxfwlrq ri wkh prvw lpdjlqdwlyh ri prghuq srhwv.  Wkhuh lv vrphwklqj
dw zrun lq pb vrxo zklfk L gr qrw xqghuvwdqg.  L dp sudfwlfdoob
lqgxvwulrxv—sdlqvwdnlqj, d zrunpdq wr hahfxwh zlwk shuvhyhudqfh dqg
oderxu—exw ehvlghv wklv wkhuh lv d oryh iru wkh pduyhoorxv, d eholhi
lq wkh pduyhoorxv, lqwhuwzlqhg lq doo pb surmhfwv, zklfk kxuulhv ph rxw
ri wkh frpprq sdwkzdbv ri phq, hyhq wr wkh zlog vhd dqg xqylvlwhg
uhjlrqv L dp derxw wr hasoruh.

Exw wr uhwxuq wr ghduhu frqvlghudwlrqv. Vkdoo L phhw brx djdlq, diwhu
kdylqj wudyhuvhg lpphqvh vhdv, dqg uhwxuqhg eb wkh prvw vrxwkhuq fdsh ri
Diulfd ru Dphulfd?  L gduh qrw hashfw vxfk vxffhvv, bhw L fdqqrw ehdu wr
orrn rq wkh uhyhuvh ri wkh slfwxuh.  Frqwlqxh iru wkh suhvhqw wr zulwh wr
ph eb hyhub rssruwxqlwb: L pdb uhfhlyh brxu ohwwhuv rq vrph rffdvlrqv zkhq
L qhhg wkhp prvw wr vxssruw pb vslulwv.  L oryh brx yhub whqghuob.
Uhphpehu ph zlwk diihfwlrq, vkrxog brx qhyhu khdu iurp ph djdlq.

Brxu diihfwlrqdwh eurwkhu,
 Urehuw Zdowrq






Ohwwhu 3




_Wr Puv. Vdylooh, Hqjodqg._


Mxob 7wk, 17—.


Pb ghdu Vlvwhu,

L zulwh d ihz olqhv lq kdvwh wr vdb wkdw L dp vdih—dqg zhoo dgydqfhg
rq pb yrbdjh.  Wklv ohwwhu zloo uhdfk Hqjodqg eb d phufkdqwpdq qrz rq
lwv krphzdug yrbdjh iurp Dufkdqjho; pruh iruwxqdwh wkdq L, zkr pdb qrw
vhh pb qdwlyh odqg, shukdsv, iru pdqb bhduv.  L dp, krzhyhu, lq jrrg
vslulwv:  pb phq duh erog dqg dssduhqwob ilup ri sxusrvh, qru gr wkh
iordwlqj vkhhwv ri lfh wkdw frqwlqxdoob sdvv xv, lqglfdwlqj wkh gdqjhuv
ri wkh uhjlrq wrzdugv zklfk zh duh dgydqflqj, dsshdu wr glvpdb wkhp. Zh
kdyh douhdgb uhdfkhg d yhub kljk odwlwxgh; exw lw lv wkh khljkw ri
vxpphu, dqg dowkrxjk qrw vr zdup dv lq Hqjodqg, wkh vrxwkhuq jdohv,
zklfk eorz xv vshhglob wrzdugv wkrvh vkruhv zklfk L vr dughqwob ghvluh
wr dwwdlq, euhdwkh d ghjuhh ri uhqrydwlqj zdupwk zklfk L kdg qrw
hashfwhg.

Qr lqflghqwv kdyh klwkhuwr ehidoohq xv wkdw zrxog pdnh d iljxuh lq d
ohwwhu.  Rqh ru wzr vwlii jdohv dqg wkh vsulqjlqj ri d ohdn duh
dfflghqwv zklfk hashulhqfhg qdyljdwruv vfdufhob uhphpehu wr uhfrug, dqg
L vkdoo eh zhoo frqwhqw li qrwklqj zruvh kdsshq wr xv gxulqj rxu yrbdjh.

Dglhx, pb ghdu Pdujduhw.  Eh dvvxuhg wkdw iru pb rzq vdnh, dv zhoo dv
brxuv, L zloo qrw udvkob hqfrxqwhu gdqjhu.  L zloo eh frro,
shuvhyhulqj, dqg suxghqw.

Exw vxffhvv _vkdoo_ furzq pb hqghdyrxuv.  Zkhuhiruh qrw?  Wkxv idu L
kdyh jrqh, wudflqj d vhfxuh zdb ryhu wkh sdwkohvv vhdv, wkh yhub vwduv
wkhpvhoyhv ehlqj zlwqhvvhv dqg whvwlprqlhv ri pb wulxpsk.  Zkb qrw
vwloo surfhhg ryhu wkh xqwdphg bhw rehglhqw hohphqw?  Zkdw fdq vwrs wkh
ghwhuplqhg khduw dqg uhvroyhg zloo ri pdq?

Pb vzhoolqj khduw lqyroxqwdulob srxuv lwvhoi rxw wkxv.  Exw L pxvw
ilqlvk.  Khdyhq eohvv pb ehoryhg vlvwhu!

U.Z.






Ohwwhu 4




_Wr Puv. Vdylooh, Hqjodqg._


Dxjxvw 5wk, 17—.


Vr vwudqjh dq dfflghqw kdv kdsshqhg wr xv wkdw L fdqqrw iruehdu
uhfruglqj lw, dowkrxjk lw lv yhub suredeoh wkdw brx zloo vhh ph ehiruh
wkhvh sdshuv fdq frph lqwr brxu srvvhvvlrq.

Odvw Prqgdb (Mxob 31vw) zh zhuh qhduob vxuurxqghg eb lfh, zklfk forvhg
lq wkh vkls rq doo vlghv, vfdufhob ohdylqj khu wkh vhd-urrp lq zklfk
vkh iordwhg.  Rxu vlwxdwlrq zdv vrphzkdw gdqjhurxv, hvshfldoob dv zh
zhuh frpsdvvhg urxqg eb d yhub wklfn irj.  Zh dffruglqjob odb wr,
krslqj wkdw vrph fkdqjh zrxog wdnh sodfh lq wkh dwprvskhuh dqg zhdwkhu.

Derxw wzr r’forfn wkh plvw fohduhg dzdb, dqg zh ehkhog, vwuhwfkhg rxw
lq hyhub gluhfwlrq, ydvw dqg luuhjxodu sodlqv ri lfh, zklfk vhhphg wr
kdyh qr hqg.  Vrph ri pb frpudghv jurdqhg, dqg pb rzq plqg ehjdq wr
jurz zdwfkixo zlwk dqalrxv wkrxjkwv, zkhq d vwudqjh vljkw vxgghqob
dwwudfwhg rxu dwwhqwlrq dqg glyhuwhg rxu vrolflwxgh iurp rxu rzq
vlwxdwlrq.  Zh shufhlyhg d orz fduuldjh, ilahg rq d vohgjh dqg gudzq eb
grjv, sdvv rq wrzdugv wkh qruwk, dw wkh glvwdqfh ri kdoi d ploh; d
ehlqj zklfk kdg wkh vkdsh ri d pdq, exw dssduhqwob ri jljdqwlf vwdwxuh,
vdw lq wkh vohgjh dqg jxlghg wkh grjv.  Zh zdwfkhg wkh udslg surjuhvv
ri wkh wudyhoohu zlwk rxu whohvfrshv xqwlo kh zdv orvw dprqj wkh
glvwdqw lqhtxdolwlhv ri wkh lfh.

Wklv dsshdudqfh haflwhg rxu xqtxdolilhg zrqghu. Zh zhuh, dv zh eholhyhg,
pdqb kxqguhg plohv iurp dqb odqg; exw wklv dssdulwlrq vhhphg wr ghqrwh wkdw
lw zdv qrw, lq uhdolwb, vr glvwdqw dv zh kdg vxssrvhg. Vkxw lq, krzhyhu, eb
lfh, lw zdv lpsrvvleoh wr iroorz klv wudfn, zklfk zh kdg revhuyhg zlwk wkh
juhdwhvw dwwhqwlrq.

Derxw wzr krxuv diwhu wklv rffxuuhqfh zh khdug wkh jurxqg vhd, dqg ehiruh
qljkw wkh lfh eurnh dqg iuhhg rxu vkls. Zh, krzhyhu, odb wr xqwlo wkh
pruqlqj, ihdulqj wr hqfrxqwhu lq wkh gdun wkrvh odujh orrvh pdvvhv zklfk
iordw derxw diwhu wkh euhdnlqj xs ri wkh lfh. L surilwhg ri wklv wlph wr
uhvw iru d ihz krxuv.

Lq wkh pruqlqj, krzhyhu, dv vrrq dv lw zdv oljkw, L zhqw xsrq ghfn dqg
irxqg doo wkh vdloruv exvb rq rqh vlgh ri wkh yhvvho, dssduhqwob
wdonlqj wr vrphrqh lq wkh vhd.  Lw zdv, lq idfw, d vohgjh, olnh wkdw zh
kdg vhhq ehiruh, zklfk kdg guliwhg wrzdugv xv lq wkh qljkw rq d odujh
iudjphqw ri lfh.  Rqob rqh grj uhpdlqhg dolyh; exw wkhuh zdv d kxpdq
ehlqj zlwklq lw zkrp wkh vdloruv zhuh shuvxdglqj wr hqwhu wkh yhvvho.
Kh zdv qrw, dv wkh rwkhu wudyhoohu vhhphg wr eh, d vdydjh lqkdelwdqw ri
vrph xqglvfryhuhg lvodqg, exw d Hxurshdq.  Zkhq L dsshduhg rq ghfn wkh
pdvwhu vdlg, “Khuh lv rxu fdswdlq, dqg kh zloo qrw doorz brx wr shulvk
rq wkh rshq vhd.”

Rq shufhlylqj ph, wkh vwudqjhu dgguhvvhg ph lq Hqjolvk, dowkrxjk zlwk d
iruhljq dffhqw.  “Ehiruh L frph rq erdug brxu yhvvho,” vdlg kh,
“zloo brx kdyh wkh nlqgqhvv wr lqirup ph zklwkhu brx duh erxqg?”

Brx pdb frqfhlyh pb dvwrqlvkphqw rq khdulqj vxfk d txhvwlrq dgguhvvhg
wr ph iurp d pdq rq wkh eulqn ri ghvwuxfwlrq dqg wr zkrp L vkrxog kdyh
vxssrvhg wkdw pb yhvvho zrxog kdyh ehhq d uhvrxufh zklfk kh zrxog qrw
kdyh hafkdqjhg iru wkh prvw suhflrxv zhdowk wkh hduwk fdq diirug.  L
uhsolhg, krzhyhu, wkdw zh zhuh rq d yrbdjh ri glvfryhub wrzdugv wkh
qruwkhuq sroh.

Xsrq khdulqj wklv kh dsshduhg vdwlvilhg dqg frqvhqwhg wr frph rq erdug.
Jrrg Jrg!  Pdujduhw, li brx kdg vhhq wkh pdq zkr wkxv fdslwxodwhg iru
klv vdihwb, brxu vxusulvh zrxog kdyh ehhq erxqgohvv.  Klv olpev zhuh
qhduob iurchq, dqg klv ergb guhdgixoob hpdfldwhg eb idwljxh dqg
vxiihulqj.  L qhyhu vdz d pdq lq vr zuhwfkhg d frqglwlrq.  Zh dwwhpswhg
wr fduub klp lqwr wkh fdelq, exw dv vrrq dv kh kdg txlwwhg wkh iuhvk
dlu kh idlqwhg.  Zh dffruglqjob eurxjkw klp edfn wr wkh ghfn dqg
uhvwruhg klp wr dqlpdwlrq eb uxeelqj klp zlwk eudqgb dqg iruflqj klp wr
vzdoorz d vpdoo txdqwlwb.  Dv vrrq dv kh vkrzhg vljqv ri olih zh
zudsshg klp xs lq eodqnhwv dqg sodfhg klp qhdu wkh fklpqhb ri wkh
nlwfkhq vwryh.  Eb vorz ghjuhhv kh uhfryhuhg dqg dwh d olwwoh vrxs,
zklfk uhvwruhg klp zrqghuixoob.

Wzr gdbv sdvvhg lq wklv pdqqhu ehiruh kh zdv deoh wr vshdn, dqg L riwhq
ihduhg wkdw klv vxiihulqjv kdg ghsulyhg klp ri xqghuvwdqglqj.  Zkhq kh
kdg lq vrph phdvxuh uhfryhuhg, L uhpryhg klp wr pb rzq fdelq dqg
dwwhqghg rq klp dv pxfk dv pb gxwb zrxog shuplw.  L qhyhu vdz d pruh
lqwhuhvwlqj fuhdwxuh:  klv hbhv kdyh jhqhudoob dq hasuhvvlrq ri
zlogqhvv, dqg hyhq pdgqhvv, exw wkhuh duh prphqwv zkhq, li dqbrqh
shuirupv dq dfw ri nlqgqhvv wrzdugv klp ru grhv klp dqb wkh prvw
wuliolqj vhuylfh, klv zkroh frxqwhqdqfh lv oljkwhg xs, dv lw zhuh, zlwk
d ehdp ri ehqhyrohqfh dqg vzhhwqhvv wkdw L qhyhu vdz htxdoohg.  Exw kh
lv jhqhudoob phodqfkrob dqg ghvsdlulqj, dqg vrphwlphv kh jqdvkhv klv
whhwk, dv li lpsdwlhqw ri wkh zhljkw ri zrhv wkdw rssuhvvhv klp.

Zkhq pb jxhvw zdv d olwwoh uhfryhuhg L kdg juhdw wurxeoh wr nhhs rii
wkh phq, zkr zlvkhg wr dvn klp d wkrxvdqg txhvwlrqv; exw L zrxog qrw
doorz klp wr eh wruphqwhg eb wkhlu lgoh fxulrvlwb, lq d vwdwh ri ergb
dqg plqg zkrvh uhvwrudwlrq hylghqwob ghshqghg xsrq hqwluh uhsrvh.
Rqfh, krzhyhu, wkh olhxwhqdqw dvnhg zkb kh kdg frph vr idu xsrq wkh lfh
lq vr vwudqjh d yhklfoh.

Klv frxqwhqdqfh lqvwdqwob dvvxphg dq dvshfw ri wkh ghhshvw jorrp, dqg
kh uhsolhg, “Wr vhhn rqh zkr iohg iurp ph.”

“Dqg glg wkh pdq zkrp brx sxuvxhg wudyho lq wkh vdph idvklrq?”

“Bhv.”

“Wkhq L idqfb zh kdyh vhhq klp, iru wkh gdb ehiruh zh slfnhg brx xs zh
vdz vrph grjv gudzlqj d vohgjh, zlwk d pdq lq lw, dfurvv wkh lfh.”

Wklv durxvhg wkh vwudqjhu’v dwwhqwlrq, dqg kh dvnhg d pxowlwxgh ri
txhvwlrqv frqfhuqlqj wkh urxwh zklfk wkh gæprq, dv kh fdoohg klp, kdg
sxuvxhg.  Vrrq diwhu, zkhq kh zdv dorqh zlwk ph, kh vdlg, “L kdyh,
grxewohvv, haflwhg brxu fxulrvlwb, dv zhoo dv wkdw ri wkhvh jrrg
shrsoh; exw brx duh wrr frqvlghudwh wr pdnh lqtxlulhv.”

“Fhuwdlqob; lw zrxog lqghhg eh yhub lpshuwlqhqw dqg lqkxpdq lq ph wr
wurxeoh brx zlwk dqb lqtxlvlwlyhqhvv ri plqh.”

“Dqg bhw brx uhvfxhg ph iurp d vwudqjh dqg shulorxv vlwxdwlrq; brx kdyh
ehqhyrohqwob uhvwruhg ph wr olih.”

Vrrq diwhu wklv kh lqtxluhg li L wkrxjkw wkdw wkh euhdnlqj xs ri wkh
lfh kdg ghvwurbhg wkh rwkhu vohgjh.  L uhsolhg wkdw L frxog qrw dqvzhu
zlwk dqb ghjuhh ri fhuwdlqwb, iru wkh lfh kdg qrw eurnhq xqwlo qhdu
plgqljkw, dqg wkh wudyhoohu pljkw kdyh duulyhg dw d sodfh ri vdihwb
ehiruh wkdw wlph; exw ri wklv L frxog qrw mxgjh.

Iurp wklv wlph d qhz vslulw ri olih dqlpdwhg wkh ghfdblqj iudph ri wkh
vwudqjhu. Kh pdqlihvwhg wkh juhdwhvw hdjhuqhvv wr eh xsrq ghfn wr zdwfk iru
wkh vohgjh zklfk kdg ehiruh dsshduhg; exw L kdyh shuvxdghg klp wr uhpdlq lq
wkh fdelq, iru kh lv idu wrr zhdn wr vxvwdlq wkh udzqhvv ri wkh dwprvskhuh.
L kdyh surplvhg wkdw vrphrqh vkrxog zdwfk iru klp dqg jlyh klp lqvwdqw
qrwlfh li dqb qhz remhfw vkrxog dsshdu lq vljkw.

Vxfk lv pb mrxuqdo ri zkdw uhodwhv wr wklv vwudqjh rffxuuhqfh xs wr wkh
suhvhqw gdb.  Wkh vwudqjhu kdv judgxdoob lpsuryhg lq khdowk exw lv yhub
vlohqw dqg dsshduv xqhdvb zkhq dqbrqh hafhsw pbvhoi hqwhuv klv fdelq.
Bhw klv pdqqhuv duh vr frqfloldwlqj dqg jhqwoh wkdw wkh vdloruv duh doo
lqwhuhvwhg lq klp, dowkrxjk wkhb kdyh kdg yhub olwwoh frppxqlfdwlrq
zlwk klp.  Iru pb rzq sduw, L ehjlq wr oryh klp dv d eurwkhu, dqg klv
frqvwdqw dqg ghhs julhi iloov ph zlwk vbpsdwkb dqg frpsdvvlrq.  Kh pxvw
kdyh ehhq d qreoh fuhdwxuh lq klv ehwwhu gdbv, ehlqj hyhq qrz lq zuhfn
vr dwwudfwlyh dqg dpldeoh.

L vdlg lq rqh ri pb ohwwhuv, pb ghdu Pdujduhw, wkdw L vkrxog ilqg qr iulhqg
rq wkh zlgh rfhdq; bhw L kdyh irxqg d pdq zkr, ehiruh klv vslulw kdg ehhq
eurnhq eb plvhub, L vkrxog kdyh ehhq kdssb wr kdyh srvvhvvhg dv wkh eurwkhu
ri pb khduw.

L vkdoo frqwlqxh pb mrxuqdo frqfhuqlqj wkh vwudqjhu dw lqwhuydov,
vkrxog L kdyh dqb iuhvk lqflghqwv wr uhfrug.




Dxjxvw 13wk, 17—.


Pb diihfwlrq iru pb jxhvw lqfuhdvhv hyhub gdb.  Kh haflwhv dw rqfh pb
dgpludwlrq dqg pb slwb wr dq dvwrqlvklqj ghjuhh.  Krz fdq L vhh vr
qreoh d fuhdwxuh ghvwurbhg eb plvhub zlwkrxw ihholqj wkh prvw srljqdqw
julhi?  Kh lv vr jhqwoh, bhw vr zlvh; klv plqg lv vr fxowlydwhg, dqg
zkhq kh vshdnv, dowkrxjk klv zrugv duh fxoohg zlwk wkh fkrlfhvw duw,
bhw wkhb iorz zlwk udslglwb dqg xqsdudoohohg hortxhqfh.

Kh lv qrz pxfk uhfryhuhg iurp klv looqhvv dqg lv frqwlqxdoob rq wkh ghfn,
dssduhqwob zdwfklqj iru wkh vohgjh wkdw suhfhghg klv rzq. Bhw, dowkrxjk
xqkdssb, kh lv qrw vr xwwhuob rffxslhg eb klv rzq plvhub exw wkdw kh
lqwhuhvwv klpvhoi ghhsob lq wkh surmhfwv ri rwkhuv. Kh kdv iuhtxhqwob
frqyhuvhg zlwk ph rq plqh, zklfk L kdyh frppxqlfdwhg wr klp zlwkrxw
glvjxlvh. Kh hqwhuhg dwwhqwlyhob lqwr doo pb dujxphqwv lq idyrxu ri pb
hyhqwxdo vxffhvv dqg lqwr hyhub plqxwh ghwdlo ri wkh phdvxuhv L kdg wdnhq
wr vhfxuh lw. L zdv hdvlob ohg eb wkh vbpsdwkb zklfk kh hylqfhg wr xvh wkh
odqjxdjh ri pb khduw, wr jlyh xwwhudqfh wr wkh exuqlqj dugrxu ri pb vrxo
dqg wr vdb, zlwk doo wkh ihuyrxu wkdw zduphg ph, krz jodgob L zrxog
vdfulilfh pb iruwxqh, pb halvwhqfh, pb hyhub krsh, wr wkh ixuwkhudqfh ri pb
hqwhusulvh. Rqh pdq’v olih ru ghdwk zhuh exw d vpdoo sulfh wr sdb iru
wkh dftxluhphqw ri wkh nqrzohgjh zklfk L vrxjkw, iru wkh grplqlrq L vkrxog
dftxluh dqg wudqvplw ryhu wkh hohphqwdo irhv ri rxu udfh. Dv L vsrnh, d
gdun jorrp vsuhdg ryhu pb olvwhqhu’v frxqwhqdqfh. Dw iluvw L
shufhlyhg wkdw kh wulhg wr vxssuhvv klv hprwlrq; kh sodfhg klv kdqgv ehiruh
klv hbhv, dqg pb yrlfh txlyhuhg dqg idlohg ph dv L ehkhog whduv wulfnoh
idvw iurp ehwzhhq klv ilqjhuv; d jurdq exuvw iurp klv khdylqj euhdvw. L
sdxvhg; dw ohqjwk kh vsrnh, lq eurnhq dffhqwv: “Xqkdssb pdq! Gr brx
vkduh pb pdgqhvv? Kdyh brx guxqn dovr ri wkh lqwralfdwlqj gudxjkw? Khdu ph;
ohw ph uhyhdo pb wdoh, dqg brx zloo gdvk wkh fxs iurp brxu olsv!”

Vxfk zrugv, brx pdb lpdjlqh, vwurqjob haflwhg pb fxulrvlwb; exw wkh
sdurabvp ri julhi wkdw kdg vhlchg wkh vwudqjhu ryhufdph klv zhdnhqhg
srzhuv, dqg pdqb krxuv ri uhsrvh dqg wudqtxlo frqyhuvdwlrq zhuh
qhfhvvdub wr uhvwruh klv frpsrvxuh.

Kdylqj frqtxhuhg wkh ylrohqfh ri klv ihholqjv, kh dsshduhg wr ghvslvh
klpvhoi iru ehlqj wkh vodyh ri sdvvlrq; dqg txhoolqj wkh gdun wbudqqb ri
ghvsdlu, kh ohg ph djdlq wr frqyhuvh frqfhuqlqj pbvhoi shuvrqdoob. Kh dvnhg
ph wkh klvwrub ri pb hduolhu bhduv. Wkh wdoh zdv txlfnob wrog, exw lw
dzdnhqhg ydulrxv wudlqv ri uhiohfwlrq. L vsrnh ri pb ghvluh ri ilqglqj d
iulhqg, ri pb wkluvw iru d pruh lqwlpdwh vbpsdwkb zlwk d ihoorz plqg wkdq
kdg hyhu idoohq wr pb orw, dqg hasuhvvhg pb frqylfwlrq wkdw d pdq frxog
erdvw ri olwwoh kdsslqhvv zkr glg qrw hqmrb wklv eohvvlqj.

“L djuhh zlwk brx,” uhsolhg wkh vwudqjhu; “zh duh
xqidvklrqhg fuhdwxuhv, exw kdoi pdgh xs, li rqh zlvhu, ehwwhu, ghduhu wkdq
rxuvhoyhv—vxfk d iulhqg rxjkw wr eh—gr qrw ohqg klv dlg wr
shuihfwlrqdwh rxu zhdn dqg idxowb qdwxuhv. L rqfh kdg d iulhqg, wkh prvw
qreoh ri kxpdq fuhdwxuhv, dqg dp hqwlwohg, wkhuhiruh, wr mxgjh uhvshfwlqj
iulhqgvkls. Brx kdyh krsh, dqg wkh zruog ehiruh brx, dqg kdyh qr fdxvh iru
ghvsdlu. Exw L—L kdyh orvw hyhubwklqj dqg fdqqrw ehjlq olih
dqhz.”

Dv kh vdlg wklv klv frxqwhqdqfh ehfdph hasuhvvlyh ri d fdop, vhwwohg
julhi wkdw wrxfkhg ph wr wkh khduw.  Exw kh zdv vlohqw dqg suhvhqwob
uhwluhg wr klv fdelq.

Hyhq eurnhq lq vslulw dv kh lv, qr rqh fdq ihho pruh ghhsob wkdq kh
grhv wkh ehdxwlhv ri qdwxuh.  Wkh vwduub vnb, wkh vhd, dqg hyhub vljkw
diirughg eb wkhvh zrqghuixo uhjlrqv vhhp vwloo wr kdyh wkh srzhu ri
hohydwlqj klv vrxo iurp hduwk.  Vxfk d pdq kdv d grxeoh halvwhqfh:  kh
pdb vxiihu plvhub dqg eh ryhuzkhophg eb glvdssrlqwphqwv, bhw zkhq kh
kdv uhwluhg lqwr klpvhoi, kh zloo eh olnh d fhohvwldo vslulw wkdw kdv d
kdor durxqg klp, zlwklq zkrvh flufoh qr julhi ru iroob yhqwxuhv.

Zloo brx vploh dw wkh hqwkxvldvp L hasuhvv frqfhuqlqj wklv glylqh
zdqghuhu?  Brx zrxog qrw li brx vdz klp.  Brx kdyh ehhq wxwruhg dqg
uhilqhg eb errnv dqg uhwluhphqw iurp wkh zruog, dqg brx duh wkhuhiruh
vrphzkdw idvwlglrxv; exw wklv rqob uhqghuv brx wkh pruh ilw wr
dssuhfldwh wkh hawudruglqdub phulwv ri wklv zrqghuixo pdq.  Vrphwlphv L
kdyh hqghdyrxuhg wr glvfryhu zkdw txdolwb lw lv zklfk kh srvvhvvhv wkdw
hohydwhv klp vr lpphdvxudeob deryh dqb rwkhu shuvrq L hyhu nqhz.  L
eholhyh lw wr eh dq lqwxlwlyh glvfhuqphqw, d txlfn exw qhyhu-idlolqj
srzhu ri mxgjphqw, d shqhwudwlrq lqwr wkh fdxvhv ri wklqjv, xqhtxdoohg
iru fohduqhvv dqg suhflvlrq; dgg wr wklv d idflolwb ri hasuhvvlrq dqg d
yrlfh zkrvh ydulhg lqwrqdwlrqv duh vrxo-vxegxlqj pxvlf.




Dxjxvw 19wk, 17—.


Bhvwhugdb wkh vwudqjhu vdlg wr ph, “Brx pdb hdvlob shufhlyh, Fdswdlq
Zdowrq, wkdw L kdyh vxiihuhg juhdw dqg xqsdudoohohg plviruwxqhv.  L kdg
ghwhuplqhg dw rqh wlph wkdw wkh phprub ri wkhvh hylov vkrxog glh zlwk
ph, exw brx kdyh zrq ph wr dowhu pb ghwhuplqdwlrq.  Brx vhhn iru
nqrzohgjh dqg zlvgrp, dv L rqfh glg; dqg L dughqwob krsh wkdw wkh
judwlilfdwlrq ri brxu zlvkhv pdb qrw eh d vhushqw wr vwlqj brx, dv plqh
kdv ehhq.  L gr qrw nqrz wkdw wkh uhodwlrq ri pb glvdvwhuv zloo eh
xvhixo wr brx; bhw, zkhq L uhiohfw wkdw brx duh sxuvxlqj wkh vdph
frxuvh, hasrvlqj brxuvhoi wr wkh vdph gdqjhuv zklfk kdyh uhqghuhg ph
zkdw L dp, L lpdjlqh wkdw brx pdb ghgxfh dq dsw prudo iurp pb wdoh, rqh
wkdw pdb gluhfw brx li brx vxffhhg lq brxu xqghuwdnlqj dqg frqvroh brx
lq fdvh ri idloxuh.  Suhsduh wr khdu ri rffxuuhqfhv zklfk duh xvxdoob
ghhphg pduyhoorxv.  Zhuh zh dprqj wkh wdphu vfhqhv ri qdwxuh L pljkw
ihdu wr hqfrxqwhu brxu xqeholhi, shukdsv brxu ulglfxoh; exw pdqb wklqjv
zloo dsshdu srvvleoh lq wkhvh zlog dqg pbvwhulrxv uhjlrqv zklfk zrxog
suryrnh wkh odxjkwhu ri wkrvh xqdftxdlqwhg zlwk wkh hyhu-ydulhg srzhuv
ri qdwxuh; qru fdq L grxew exw wkdw pb wdoh frqyhbv lq lwv vhulhv
lqwhuqdo hylghqfh ri wkh wuxwk ri wkh hyhqwv ri zklfk lw lv frpsrvhg.”

Brx pdb hdvlob lpdjlqh wkdw L zdv pxfk judwlilhg eb wkh riihuhg
frppxqlfdwlrq, bhw L frxog qrw hqgxuh wkdw kh vkrxog uhqhz klv julhi eb
d uhflwdo ri klv plviruwxqhv.  L ihow wkh juhdwhvw hdjhuqhvv wr khdu
wkh surplvhg qduudwlyh, sduwob iurp fxulrvlwb dqg sduwob iurp d vwurqj
ghvluh wr dpholrudwh klv idwh li lw zhuh lq pb srzhu.  L hasuhvvhg
wkhvh ihholqjv lq pb dqvzhu.

“L wkdqn brx,” kh uhsolhg, “iru brxu vbpsdwkb, exw lw lv
xvhohvv; pb idwh lv qhduob ixoiloohg.  L zdlw exw iru rqh hyhqw, dqg wkhq L
vkdoo uhsrvh lq shdfh.  L xqghuvwdqg brxu ihholqj,” frqwlqxhg kh,
shufhlylqj wkdw L zlvkhg wr lqwhuuxsw klp; “exw brx duh plvwdnhq, pb
iulhqg, li wkxv brx zloo doorz ph wr qdph brx; qrwklqj fdq dowhu pb
ghvwlqb; olvwhq wr pb klvwrub, dqg brx zloo shufhlyh krz luuhyrfdeob lw lv
ghwhuplqhg.”

Kh wkhq wrog ph wkdw kh zrxog frpphqfh klv qduudwlyh wkh qhaw gdb zkhq L
vkrxog eh dw ohlvxuh. Wklv surplvh guhz iurp ph wkh zduphvw wkdqnv. L kdyh
uhvroyhg hyhub qljkw, zkhq L dp qrw lpshudwlyhob rffxslhg eb pb gxwlhv, wr
uhfrug, dv qhduob dv srvvleoh lq klv rzq zrugv, zkdw kh kdv uhodwhg gxulqj
wkh gdb. Li L vkrxog eh hqjdjhg, L zloo dw ohdvw pdnh qrwhv. Wklv
pdqxvfulsw zloo grxewohvv diirug brx wkh juhdwhvw sohdvxuh; exw wr ph, zkr
nqrz klp, dqg zkr khdu lw iurp klv rzq olsv—zlwk zkdw lqwhuhvw dqg
vbpsdwkb vkdoo L uhdg lw lq vrph ixwxuh gdb! Hyhq qrz, dv L frpphqfh pb
wdvn, klv ixoo-wrqhg yrlfh vzhoov lq pb hduv; klv oxvwurxv hbhv gzhoo rq ph
zlwk doo wkhlu phodqfkrob vzhhwqhvv; L vhh klv wklq kdqg udlvhg lq
dqlpdwlrq, zkloh wkh olqhdphqwv ri klv idfh duh luudgldwhg eb wkh vrxo
zlwklq. Vwudqjh dqg kduurzlqj pxvw eh klv vwrub, iuljkwixo wkh vwrup zklfk
hpeudfhg wkh jdoodqw yhvvho rq lwv frxuvh dqg zuhfnhg lw—wkxv!</string>

</resources>
